QUESTIONS = [
  {
    "question": "A program design entirely for destruction and havoc is known as ___",
    "options": {
      "A": "Worm",
      "B": "Virus",
      "C": "Macro virus",
      "D": "Trojan horse"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Switching device of first generation computer is_______",
    "options": {
      "A": "Vacuum tubes",
      "B": "Transistors",
      "C": "IC",
      "D": "VLSI"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In most software packages, the function key F1 is used to run the _____program.",
    "options": {
      "A": "RUN",
      "B": "LEAVE",
      "C": "EXIT",
      "D": "HELP"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "________are peripheral devices used to digitize artwork, photographs, text, or other items from hard copy.",
    "answer": "Scanners",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The chips have data written on them during manufacturing that tells the CPU what to do when the PC is switched on is referred to as",
    "options": {
      "A": "RAM",
      "B": "ROMAN",
      "C": "ROM",
      "D": "READ"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Operating systems the primary interface between the user and the rest of the system is its",
    "answer": "Command Interpreter",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____ instruction directs the computer to accept data from a specific input device and store it in a specific location in the store",
    "options": {
      "A": "output",
      "B": "input",
      "C": "sideput",
      "D": "print"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first stage of program debugging is ________",
    "answer": "Desk checking",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "LSI stands for ____________",
    "options": {
      "A": "All of the options ",
      "B": "Large Scale Integration ",
      "C": "Length Scale Integration ",
      "D": "Long Scale Integration "
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A program designed entirely for destruction and havoc is known as ________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Worm",
      "B": "Micro Virus",
      "C": "Virus",
      "D": "Trojan Horse"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a type  of programing language? ",
    "options": {
      "A": "All of the options ",
      "B": "Machine language",
      "C": "High level Symbolic language   ",
      "D": "Assembly language"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Switching device of fifth generation computer is_______",
    "options": {
      "A": "Transistors ",
      "B": "IC",
      "C": "VLSI",
      "D": "Vacuum tuve"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "POP stands for\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.",
    "answer": "Point of Presence",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A computer that uses the services of another computer is a\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026",
    "answer": "client",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. multi-user collection of information.",
    "answer": "database",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "BBS stands for\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.",
    "answer": "Bulleting board system",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "ISP stands for\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026",
    "answer": "Internet Service Providers",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. is a software tool that you use to look at web pages.",
    "answer": "browser",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \u2026\u2026.. only has a range of approximately one-kilometre.",
    "answer": "LAN",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "WAN stands for __________",
    "answer": "Wide Area Networks",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "When errors are detected in a program, a series of diagnostics referred to as an error ____ list is generated by the language translator",
    "options": {
      "A": "prompt",
      "B": "error",
      "C": "display",
      "D": "message"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Simplification of program maintenance is an advantage of program ____",
    "answer": "documentation",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "This short cut key combination deletes a line in most text documents.",
    "options": {
      "A": "CTRL + Y",
      "B": "CTRL + Z",
      "C": "CTRL + D",
      "D": "CTRL + P"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In ___ alignment, the text along the right side of the paragraph appears ragged",
    "answer": "left",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Excel, chart ____ allow you to print a chart that is separate from data",
    "options": {
      "A": "table",
      "B": "rows",
      "C": "sheets",
      "D": "pages"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A chart symbol that represents a single data point is data ____.",
    "answer": "marker",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Chart ____feature leads a user through a step-by-step process to create a chart and displays sample views as you build it",
    "options": {
      "A": "witch",
      "B": "wishes",
      "C": "wizard",
      "D": "lord"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "AutoShapes button in Microsoft PowerPoint provides access to over ____ shapes",
    "answer": 150,
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Nigeria, computers are built to operate with a voltage of ____",
    "options": {
      "A": "280v",
      "B": "260v",
      "C": "240v",
      "D": "245v"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Computer is fast becoming the universal machine of the\u2026\u2026",
    "answer": "21st Century",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 is referred to facts about a person, object or place e.g. name, age, complexion, school, class, height etc.",
    "answer": "data",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is referred to as processed data or a meaningful statement e.g. Net pay of workers, examination results of students, list of successful candidates in an examination or interview etc.",
    "answer": "Information",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \u2026\u2026\u2026.. of data processing involves the use of chalk, wall, pen pencil and the like.",
    "options": {
      "A": "ancient method",
      "B": "mechanical method",
      "C": "mechanized method",
      "D": "manual method"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \u2026\u2026\u2026 of data processing involves the use of machines such as typewriter, roneo machines, adding machines and the like.",
    "answer": "Mechanical method",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____ is a default file extension for all excel files",
    "options": {
      "A": "DOCX",
      "B": "WRD",
      "C": "XLSX",
      "D": "TXT"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is not a basic classification of Computer Software?",
    "options": {
      "A": "All of the options",
      "B": "MS software",
      "C": "Presentation software",
      "D": "Control software"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a function of an operating system",
    "options": {
      "A": "All of the options",
      "B": "Allocates resources",
      "C": "Monitors Activities",
      "D": "Manages disks and files"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A file name in Microsoft Word can have up to ____ characters",
    "options": {
      "A": 255,
      "B": 256,
      "C": 250,
      "D": 286
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "CPU history is closely tied to ____",
    "options": {
      "A": "Linux",
      "B": "Nokia",
      "C": "Intel",
      "D": "IBM"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Light pen is an example of _______ devices",
    "options": {
      "A": "Output",
      "B": "Auxilliary",
      "C": "Storage",
      "D": "Input"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "____is one of the four major data processing functions of a computer",
    "options": {
      "A": "storing the data or information",
      "B": "gathering data",
      "C": "processing data into information",
      "D": "All of the options"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which smaller unit of the CPU directs and coordinates all activities within it and determines the sequence in which instructions are executed.",
    "options": {
      "A": "ALU",
      "B": "CU",
      "C": "Processor",
      "D": "All of the options"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The speed of a CPU is measured in _____",
    "options": {
      "A": "Velocity",
      "B": "Frequency",
      "C": "Hertz",
      "D": "Megahertz"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "First generation CPUs occurred within year",
    "options": {
      "A": "1930s -1940s",
      "B": "1950s -1960s",
      "C": "1940s -1950s",
      "D": "1960s -1970s"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Control key on the computer keyboard is denoted by ____",
    "options": {
      "A": "ESC",
      "B": "CTRL",
      "C": "CTR",
      "D": "ALT"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following features can be seen in the front of the system unit?",
    "options": {
      "A": "All of the options",
      "B": "Turbo Button",
      "C": "Power On/Off",
      "D": "Key Lock"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The CPU is also known as_",
    "options": {
      "A": "All of the options",
      "B": "The Processor",
      "C": "The central processing unit",
      "D": "The Brain"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "______ is a large array of words or bytes, each with its own address",
    "options": {
      "A": "Letters",
      "B": "Binary",
      "C": "Processor",
      "D": "Memory"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "___is one of the four major data processing functions of a computer",
    "options": {
      "A": "gathering data",
      "B": "processing data into information",
      "C": "storing the data or information",
      "D": "All of the options"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A computer that provides services to other computers in a network is called ___.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Server",
      "B": "Computer Unit",
      "C": "Workstation",
      "D": "Node"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "____ is the slowest computer printer known.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Inkjet Printer",
      "B": "Dotmatrix Printer",
      "C": "Laser Printer",
      "D": "Daisywheel Printer"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ system is the term used for a collection of processors that do not share memory or a clock.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Uncontrol",
      "B": "General",
      "C": "Centralized",
      "D": "Distributed"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A _____ is a computer program that accepts a source program in one high level language",
    "options": {
      "A": "Translator",
      "B": "Assembler",
      "C": "Complier",
      "D": "Interpreter"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The general term for Assemblers, Interpreters and Compliers is ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "language Programs",
      "B": "Machine language",
      "C": "Operating systems",
      "D": "Language translators"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The keys combination to press to restart the computer using the keys on the keyboard are:",
    "options": {
      "A": "Ctrl+Shift+Del Keys",
      "B": "Del+Shift+Del Keys",
      "C": "Shift+Ctrl+Del Keys",
      "D": "Ctrl+Alt+Del Keys"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A collection of related information defined by its creator is called _____",
    "options": {
      "A": "All of the options",
      "B": "Folder",
      "C": "Document",
      "D": "File"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Management information systems (MIS) _____",
    "options": {
      "A": "process business transactions (e.g., time cards, payments, orders, etc.)",
      "B": "create and share documents that support day-today office activities",
      "C": "use the transaction data to produce information needed by managers to run the business",
      "D": "all of the options"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most common tool used in restricting access to a computer system is ___",
    "options": {
      "A": "Access-control software",
      "B": "Biometrics",
      "C": "User logins",
      "D": "Passwords"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____ when get downloaded on computer scans the hard drive for personal information and the user\\'s internet browsing habits?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Backdoors",
      "B": "Spyware",
      "C": "Malware",
      "D": "Key-logger"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____ refers to a mechanism for controlling the access of programs, processes, or users to the resources defined by a computer controls to be imposed, together with some means of enforcement.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Prevention",
      "B": "Process",
      "C": "Protection",
      "D": "Password"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a type of printer?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Inkjet",
      "B": "Dot-matrix",
      "C": "All of the options",
      "D": "Laserjet"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A removable magnetic disc that holds information is called ____",
    "options": {
      "A": "Hard drive",
      "B": "Floppy disk",
      "C": "Monitor",
      "D": "Portable"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Second generation CPUs occurred within year",
    "options": {
      "A": "1930s -1940s",
      "B": "1960s -1970s",
      "C": "1950s -1960s",
      "D": "1940s -1950s"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Online real-time systems became popular in the ___ Generation",
    "options": {
      "A": "Second",
      "B": "Third",
      "C": "First",
      "D": "Fourth"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not part of the Input/Output system?",
    "options": {
      "A": "A buffer caching system",
      "B": "None of the options",
      "C": "Drivers for specific hardware devices",
      "D": "A general device driver code"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following are type of programming language except\u00a0",
    "options": {
      "A": "High level symbolic language",
      "B": "Assembly language",
      "C": "Machine language",
      "D": "FORTRAN"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not included in Management Information System ?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Strategic support systems",
      "B": "Controlling and operational planning support systems",
      "C": "expert knowledge capture support system.",
      "D": "Tactical support systems"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ are computer programs designed to gain root or administrative access to computers.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Malware",
      "B": "Rootkits",
      "C": "Backdoors",
      "D": "Spyware"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In most software packages, the function key F1 is used to run the _____program.",
    "options": {
      "A": "RUN",
      "B": "LEAVE",
      "C": "EXIT",
      "D": "HELP"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "________are peripheral devices used to digitize artwork, photographs, text, or other items from hard copy.",
    "answer": "Scanners",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The chips have data written on them during manufacturing that tells the CPU what to do when the PC is switched on is referred to as",
    "options": {
      "A": "RAM",
      "B": "ROMAN",
      "C": "ROM",
      "D": "READ"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Operating systems the primary interface between the user and the rest of the system is its",
    "answer": "Command Interpreter",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____ instruction directs the computer to accept data from a specific input device and store it in a specific location in the store",
    "options": {
      "A": "output",
      "B": "input",
      "C": "sideput",
      "D": "print"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first stage of program debugging is ________",
    "answer": "Desk checking",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "When errors are detected in a program, a series of diagnostics referred to as an error ____ list is generated by the language translator",
    "options": {
      "A": "prompt",
      "B": "error",
      "C": "display",
      "D": "message"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Simplification of program maintenance is an advantage of program ____",
    "answer": "documentation",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "This short cut key combination deletes a line in most text documents.",
    "options": {
      "A": "CTRL + Y",
      "B": "CTRL + Z",
      "C": "CTRL + D",
      "D": "CTRL + P"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In ___ alignment, the text along the right side of the paragraph appears ragged",
    "answer": "left",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Excel, chart ____ allow you to print a chart that is separate from data",
    "options": {
      "A": "table",
      "B": "rows",
      "C": "sheets",
      "D": "pages"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A chart symbol that represents a single data point is data ____.",
    "answer": "marker",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Chart ____feature leads a user through a step-by-step process to create a chart and displays sample views as you build it",
    "options": {
      "A": "witch",
      "B": "wishes",
      "C": "wizard",
      "D": "lord"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "AutoShapes button in Microsoft PowerPoint provides access to over ____ shapes",
    "answer": 150,
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Nigeria, computers are built to operate with a voltage of ____",
    "options": {
      "A": "280v",
      "B": "260v",
      "C": "240v",
      "D": "245v"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Computer is fast becoming the universal machine of the\u2026\u2026",
    "answer": "21st Century",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 is referred to facts about a person, object or place e.g. name, age, complexion, school, class, height etc.",
    "answer": "data",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is referred to as processed data or a meaningful statement e.g. Net pay of workers, examination results of students, list of successful candidates in an examination or interview etc.",
    "answer": "Information",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \u2026\u2026\u2026.. of data processing involves the use of chalk, wall, pen pencil and the like.",
    "options": {
      "A": "ancient method",
      "B": "mechanical method",
      "C": "mechanized method",
      "D": "manual method"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \u2026\u2026\u2026 of data processing involves the use of machines such as typewriter, roneo machines, adding machines and the like.",
    "answer": "Mechanical method",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "MAN stands for\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..",
    "options": {
      "A": "Metropolitan Area Network",
      "B": "Men Area Network",
      "C": "Media Area Network",
      "D": "Macro Area Network"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. is an application program used to create presentations.",
    "answer": "PowerPoint",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Excel is a software application that provides an\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. or worksheet environment.",
    "answer": "electronic spreadsheet",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. consists of information written in tabular form.",
    "options": {
      "A": "photoshoot",
      "B": "ms word ",
      "C": "spreedsheet",
      "D": "drawing"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Text files can be created and modified with the aid of a special program called an \u2026\u2026",
    "answer": "editor",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "CPU stands for____",
    "options": {
      "A": "none of the options",
      "B": "Centrical Processing Unit",
      "C": "Core Processing Unit",
      "D": "Central Processing Unit"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. is a graphical representation of the major steps of work in process. It displays in separate boxes the essential steps of the program and shows by means of arrows the directions of information flow.",
    "answer": "Flowchart",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026.. is a program design aid that serves the function of a flowchart in expressing the detailed logic of a program.",
    "answer": "Pseudocode",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 tables are used to analyze a problem.",
    "options": {
      "A": "tree",
      "B": "thinking ",
      "C": "decision",
      "D": "tall"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. is a set of rules for carrying out calculation either by hand or a machine.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Pseudocode",
      "B": "Flowchart",
      "C": "Action Stub",
      "D": "An algorithm"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. of the program should be developed at every stage of the programming cycle.",
    "answer": "Documentation",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is referred to as processed data or a meaningful statement e.g. Net pay of workers, examination results of students, list of successful candidates in an examination or interview etc.",
    "answer": "Information",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The collection of files that make up an application in Visual basic is known as a _____",
    "options": {
      "A": "Coding",
      "B": "Folder",
      "C": "Project",
      "D": "Listing"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "____ is a programming design that serves the function of a flowchart in expressing the detailed logic of a program.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Algorithm",
      "B": "Decision table",
      "C": "Pseudocode",
      "D": "DFD"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "____ is a finite sequence of operations which gives an unambiguous method of solving a problem",
    "options": {
      "A": "Programming",
      "B": "DFD",
      "C": "Algorithm",
      "D": "Flowchart"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  }
]